today is tuesday september twentieth
says lecture seven for rehearsal
uh... you know
that point anyway
so make sure we are walking into i
received today
to use that through firefox inside of a
virtual machine rather than
firefox
from the women's side
so that you're just inside the virtual
machine
yep install child so i can
inside about firefox
by the end of semester realty so used to
a song titles or that uh... doctor in
your sleep
so it's failing on you
you're on
are you in the gas wireless
or e-commerce because wireless marching
through
that's why it doesn't need to use
landline
higher exercise
too many networks in firewalls
as per the best of alleged after
possibly reset print here
for
erroneous nickname
so you need to change the name to be
something over
research tools at the bottom line three
three four star
click there and change your name to your
name
says already have probably a richer
tools for the twenty guys so you all
need to make sure you have to agree
jointed login digital insight into
machines
right
excellent
everybody when you if you get the a
romance name
it means that chod zilla has using the
false name if you could bottom left
corner of your screen
it says research tools with a little
arrow pointing down click that button
select change name
and type in your username
that he'd message t
research tools and you were on hai or
s_s_i_
you can use that one morning instead
attach up there on the screen attitude
connect
eight performers and has a scientific
command syntax
which is frustrating
and it's not very pretty
so did you open firefox
and did you go to tools
since there's no chat though and there
you'll need to go to add-ons
and there's a search window history has
received three there
quick so and there it's all along
weren't
you enter
research
you can click the top one if you speak
spanish french or
polish you can pick that language but
click install for the right of it
and then
once installed you out there to ask you
restart you restart tool
ctf
your change the name of that
so put down
changed and go ahead and changing
seated as such
tonight after you had the uh... told
don't forget to restart
firefox or the adam will be available
yet
america constantly
perpetually electorate
highly is not doing a fifth star annex
new hampshire
eight years ago pick that
women uh...
adult
are you can try it
it give it a go
curator
it's its own personal machine so usually
try at the close up you can always
reboot the virtual machines turn over
thinking oh and now you can join
uh...
you it refers
channel illinois
now if we tell you
see you most likely are you on the
inside that worked on
your guest
so then if you're probably city cebu
to use robots yeah
yet that and put myself in the house and
one suspects that for class starts that
young
connecting you know
yet so there's
you will not be able to know whether
they're faced even gets that from the
test at work you have to have to cease
to resist fools running
what you can do for right now from the
guest network isn't necessary to covert
interest was run i_r_s_ inside
and it's going to be a horrible
text-based clients answer if you have
everything there's some really awesome
there's a whole bunch of the awesome
uplands
edison
post afflict renewed has one built and
then
post-cold
so it's a king internal server error
protected to bring out your said
deliveries of open up a new open up a
new terminal essays to research tools
and then run i_r_s_ inside on research
tools your basic going into the
ineffective domain
contracts it happened there don't end up
going out to the world
uh...
from when the classes
considered prosecuted
elicit different itself
that's the old one
and now you can get now you're not
touching the free no your attaching to
what's up on the white board up there
research tools so sick on the image
now you're catching up to now go ahead
and type in the second command the joint
command
so go ahead and do the unit research
tools drawing
to change that game
titanium
it's big
it gets very confused when there's a lot
of people changed
so you could soon
type of pain
quite telcel
and start over
e yeah
which has a lot
now started up again
change your name
click ok
t_v_ attach
digital don't work yeah they want
sliders
musicman
yes but you need to use your username
otherwise i won't
met with you
you misspelled though join
so there's missed
in your community rerun the join
commands up on the platform
see how it says
slash joint space
pound u_n_ each research tools
you missed the u_n_ h
where i had to start here if you all go
to the website for the class i just pace
of the into the i received
if you go into the air
i've now posted
the lecture notes for
lecture seven today
and today getting the audio up there if
you
winery listen to the lecture hit pause
what not
replayed
there's antifreeze
and forays for mac users architect in
new york for an excuse ears
has a question
we are not streaming live
i go through and i tend to remove an
half an hour from each client's of
i guess i go through each person dot you
would hear me say the same thing took up
a little people
minor variations that we thought that
go ahead and open up that the maxim org
boden file
at the end of class
you gonna start
working on the homework that we do it at
the end of thursday
and that will be indymac sort mode
so you be actually typing something that
workload and then submitting
the homework that way
it's due at five p_m_ so that if you
need to talk to you for after class on
thursday but i'll be around and i can
give you some help to get stuck
soul jump in today's class
couple these items that are on your come
directly from questions from you all
questions are great
and we're gonna go take a look acts
even two men page section the scroll
down just a little ladies
oftentimes
if you've got was for computers
and especially if you're in this
classroom working when there's no one
else here
there's no reason you can't log into
computers and have one showing
documentation everyone being at work
small screens can be kinda frustrating
sometimes
so one way that you could use that
multiple screens
those men because we've been looking at
are available online
and if you click on
uh... the admin pages dot you plenty dot
com
this is got all of the man pages four
you're going to so you get there not
installed machine we haven't sort of the
package if they should be here
we're using the version of the burned
too
means
eleven point oh four
it's also called
nadeem so you'll see an a_t_t_ why they
go through the alphabet
and their they worked and on this one
the next one starts with an how
and there's a search for me
search firms hiding over the right here
if you get an error screen i'd be
and his reform we can type whatever we
feel like for me
then pages
i'm gonna pick one at random
max
this is attachment you'll be using in
the homework
there is a person have been maxim each
of these
the click on the one for ninety eleven
point of for min max one
here tells you
all the main page information for that
particular commands
one very weird thing
is if you look at the g_n_p_ version for
some reason they've gone back up
full bunch of version so if we go
you can have a foreign power back in
time for getting a ten point and one and
look at the same and page
you'll see that there's a newer version
of g_n_p_ so i think they had a minor
quirk in their packaging
so if that man pages somehow weird or
week old
and that page you're looking at you can
jump in look at different versions of
you going to
and see what the men face looks like
cycle event and will be coming out
next month
and say here's garmin max ten page for
the upcoming
release
and you can read through all the options
so that we could have it up on the
screen if you're working thing here or
if you happen to be some orignal out
there with him on theirs
it's nice to people i have
that up on a separate computer if you
need
you to be reading about things
so i want to show you another resource
that's called safari books online
there is a ton of material here
uh... you an agent
our library has hit or miss on how the
material it's missing a lot of stuff
that we would like to have for research
but it does have some really great
resources and one of them
if you're doing stuff related to the
nixon computers
is called safari books online and
books can get very expensive very fast
if they're
between twenty and sixty dollars a
typical
computer book
that's gonna add up very fast
while you're here you have access to
computer books
through this service called safari books
online and when you leave
if you're not a place that has a fari
books and you still think you need us to
send you can get a personal account
but it's a lot cheaper than buying tons
of books and this way you get to see
often so if we take a quick look
if you have it is the u_s_ liar or four
you have to access it through black
forum
solar open this link in the window you
got a blackboard
quick login
use my rearview managed login
saddam walked into blackboard
very exciting tree both on the sphere
class registration
as a library tab here's the second one
click on library
and then there's connected databases mrs
very twisted long path to get to it
over on the right
and databases there's passed through t
and what with the top one is safari
books online
so if you're looking for material on
any sort of software
look here first it won't have things
mister like if you wanna book on carrots
or or g_i_s_ afoot arounds
there probably won't be anything here
but if you want a book on python
so you're using mac subjects ellen
having trouble figure something out
there's all kinds of technical books in
here
on programming in using software
there's lots of categories or you can
just search for example
today
we're using email x so you can type the
maxim that search engine appear
okay see saggy max in search window
click search
you'll now see
a few books on key max come up
the first reading about the libraries
they say here sir databases
which ones are relevant to us isn't
obvious
sunshine point out a few as we go
through the semester
and you can search for books here
and you can start reading the book right
online
eight very big drawback to safari you
can't basilica p_d_ effort the book
and go take a look at it
so you have to have internet
and be able to log in to you in age to
get access to spark plugs
trouble service unavailable
uh... are you actually login and yet
you're logged in
perhaps because we all love him so far
at the same time it's flipping out
it may have died
a limit on the number of users at one
time
i've never seen this before
if you come back later you'll probably
be able to get into safari
i've never seen this before but
when we do this class and we all have
nineteen or twenty people try to log
into one service that once then we find
out there's limits on things
usi quick to read the entire book before
we order
we need more information not all be
there for you
that were not in use it right now
but if you want to bone up on any topics
for those who aren't native english
american speakers means learn more about
sorry for my use of vocabulary
will close that up
so that safari tech
books on one there's lots of other
resource in library who had a few more
throughout the semester
with little regard having journals but
i apologize for after
survive dot
last time there was a question
about
finding out which software is installed
on the computer and which software you
can install
for you want to
i've written a section up on that we
won't go through it in detail
is there for you to read through few
want to see how to do it
it talks about the command mime-version
says commands like d package d_p_ cagey
how to search through things
at the bottom there's a screen shot
showing you that
you can also get to something called the
synoptic
package manger this is a graphical tools
for
viewing packages installing them if you
are
feeling like you question when i
graphical interface or girly
its easy way research first often dot
remember the family stuff
but the family stuff is very handy
an hour trip into the meat of today
and that's
uh... topic
called he max which is a text editor
and i'm in truckee straight into working
with something called workman
maybe a little background as to what's
going on and why im
really shouldn't have you guys learn
org rodent and seeing if you want to use
it in your little research
i tend to keep
notebooks i thought about bringing him
in but there be extracted higher paper
notebooks
for research
going back to there early nineties when
i was undergraduate
cap paper
and you have
a lot of author pages he built up over
the years and you want to search the
paper if you don't remember what year
you did something
or you know how otherwise find it can
take forever to find something in a free
and all of your own notes which is fun
but not
so in two thousand four
when i was at nasa
one of the other engineers that i was
working with suggested why don't you
create text file for every year
and just paste notes in their largest
are pasting stuff
and then you can search surrey and with
run that command public wept
to search for text
you can run things like crap on it and
say
i'd like to see all the places that
ideas dot workout command
virtually all the tricks that i do with
it over the last year's
you can start searching stuff very
quickly
so in two thousand four you can see
perry's work out all my
log files
and the text files got some
bits and pieces but in two thousand four
at twelve thousand wanted notes
last year
i actually had
thirty one thousand lines of notes
that might seem scary but a lot of that
is cut and paste
so if you work in a shell you can just
copy which you detect history
select the taxed
peace in your notes
you just generate a hundred lines of
notes about what you've done for the
last couple hours
being very stressed out and have it
sit down and think and right and
there's a lot of time on that
so you can see that certain days you
affair paper that i want to show you a
sample of one of my log files
is actually can output
now they switched at work mon
from st taxed in two thousand ten
i've actually got something that's
indexed
it's got search mechanisms dot table of
contents
and i don't have to do any extra worked
to create those things
to be able to go in and mark things as
you go electric republican and say give
me everything about topic is something
that we're going through the great at
actually no
that several of the graduate students
here
have used this
for organizing a thesis defense for
keeping notes for planning for things
you can build checklists kindness for if
you go to see of the things need to do
before and after endearing
occurs
it's a really gamh
system has usable and lots of different
ways on the show you some ways that i'll
use it
and a few adopt this
you'll find ways that work for you to
the different than what i do
so don't just think about what i'm doing
there may be a need for something for
organization
you like
that works well in the system let me
show you an example of one of my life
files
please do not the intended by the volume
take on notes
so this is the html or web output that
comes from new york mode file
and you can see that i do it
i still really boring format where i do
an entry per day
and i have sub entries for topics
you can see all sorts of strange things
in here
might jump down to them
some injuries and start showing you
just a little bit about what's going on
then
what you're seeing are my for centuries
that i made part of what was more
important so they're not necessarily
always the fanciest
but you could have little blocks attacks
to complete tables then
you could have web links to anything
that you need we have delicious but
you're always necessary when i have
something
intuitive separate from your notes if
you want to have them together here
you can just drop in links email
addresses
be able to put on them
you can include pictures
you actually do calculations in this
how you can link out stables happened to
you column after psyche wouldn't
spreadsheets
so you can see there's all kinds of
different things in here things are
marched to do you
and their marks and the more marked on
here he said here's working with some
ships
crews out way out of what was going on
for that time
certain lots of really exciting things
you can do with this and then when you
start going up
notes throughout europe he says you can
go back
to the beginning of your thesis since he
was going on
and this is
the most valuable when you've been doing
it for a long time and shorting out
you have some information in there but
it's not really a database for your head
if you've been doing this for a year to
start having enough information that you
can start counting on this and
for me it's very hard to do research
without these notes around
i am always going back and trying to
remember exactly what i did for people
thing or get reacquainted with the topic
it's been a year or two things i've done
a particular thing
so for example if you're working on a
particular aspect of say calibrating a
multitude sonar
and the last time you calibrated sonar
was three years ago
there might be things that you're going
to forget
if you've got detailed notes like this
immediate picture of the set up a few
things like that you jump back to you
know it's find it quickly
and you can get yourself back up to
speed because
a lot of what we do this for the
complicated
so that's an example of it
an easy thing to do a lot we uh...
did all of these commands before
last time so hopefully you all have done
this if you have it right now
will skip this is not worry about are
right now
ask me later on and i can help you set
this up
these commands make sure that you've got
the tools available
to make a nice html export for the
webform and to make a p_f_ from your
notes
so let's jump in
to opening up files eighty maximal start
creating some files that are or quoted
samples amherst to learn by doing
i don't even know how many mansuri
he maxim their artist huge amounts but
where to start small
by example
and will see what we can create pretty
quickly
to go ahead and start the max up at the
top
it's that weird
blue purple circle with that
squiggly ian some strange slash through
it
that we had to our toolbar last time
weird rates would go as they can you
supposed to be uh...
cal like critter
you know it's everywhere
city max
came about before microsoft windows or
before mac o_s_
miss that so has
a little bit different terminology as
you can hear some funny things like
visiting files
let's go ahead
and open a directory
edges pick research tools for starts
sony max actually lets you c directories
parade inside of what you're doing
zvornik is white if possible
especially with our research tools name
is an awfully long username
so it will be it will be using this
to manage files in folders later on
you can scroll open down
you can press and her on a file or
direct real-world put up
is uh... they retain tools called juror
at noon
but let's go ahead and visit the new
file
correct create something new
amrita collette example
dot or
now i told you a four that extensions at
the end of pollens are just tents
so if you were to pick something else
that you could force it to be at work
mode file
here crusade dot work at the end you max
is gonna switch into org mode
and get it set up for
working with this right away so it's a
it's not a forced that's a hint
so example dot org
and i have a blank screen
and you have no idea what to do
but will just start off with
some of the basic commands
now if you look at the top there's menus
like other tech senators
of course
are you able to open a file yet
if it's a little getting used to be a
so katie find file
typing example dot org
because the cancelled story over
visit you filed
anti big sample flowers
press enteral okay
sampled on board
from going too fast into too much
weaving and
now i see some of you a back seat open
something called example without the dot
work on the end
if you do not make sure you do file
visited file again
so you've actually open up the wrong
thing
civil to file and extreme example that
worked on there
now if your window is going down below
the bottom
which happens a lot here
so what you're seeing
you can
ceremony later on this thing
and write that purple machine to get
more three repeated before spring moon
now you can see all
bt max whenever you wanna make sure you
can see the bottom out the window
mister gregg
there's a couple menus at the top ten a
change
so depending on what you're doing
new items will appear up at the top
inorg load
you'll see that this one appears at the
top and i'm gonna make my window
permalink change the size that went into
the consumer mom
what is work going
we're gonna learn by doing
so great now
it's just a particular mode of the text
editor is in
and it gives you more features
saw kothrud explain it more later on it
imax is at exeter and a lot more you
don't do this but i will show you really
quickly
this is also the mat-su
so if you're up late actress
it also has tetris in there
it's a super powerful tak center it's a
little bit different than most tech
centers it used to seeing
it's got all kinds of strange things
like that has complained that they can
save my score
that's okay because i stuff
or no dick is uh... subset
it's a extra thing indy max that lets us
do outlines an organization's and
have hyperlinks free
web your als that actually from click on
so you're gonna see similar coming on
it's a little hard to get the sense of
that and facing a bunch of different
modes happen there's a text mode is just
born final taxed there's a mode for
python
when you were adding text for
fitzpatrick python code there's a motor
sian fortran
matlab
and it gives you different features
depending on what you're doing so
workload is the
organizational mode
it's uh... baseless are opposite
outlining tool
so if you go and report
you can say new heading
and it's going to look a lot like when
we did the wiki
so there's been a little special
characters the going you're taxed
that give you special features
unfortunately most of these things the
called markup languages of various sorts
they're all slightly different
height you'll find that i actually make
a lot of the states where i type in the
media wiki
highlighting tax for example
if intermixing bolbo by often type in
the wrong thing
because i used to many different markup
languages but
there's menu items for each one of them
or you can just type in straight
services
and first
so we use the command to do that
you could have done it very easily with
this typing it so we can always say you
heading
second
and you can make sub headings by adding
more stars
doesn't look like very much is not very
helpful in this mode
there's a lot of stuff hiding behind the
scenes here that you can do
so if you had if you're going or self an
outline
say another style
heading and i
if you go up to this one with the star
on it
and the two sub headings
magically i'm even disappear
and that's the they came back
what i didn't when i first the tabs
and the tabs he
does what's called folding seeking
clocks your outline
if you have a lot of outline structure
you can make things come and go
and he seemed a little three dots that
appear after things
that means there's entries underneath
that
so the idea being if you work in a very
big document you can clock suggest to
the top level
items and then you can start working
through the documents
let's make a little bit more she is able
before we go and create our first
publication
for just type in some random text and
hispanic he's a whole bunch
press enter
let's go ahead and
say that
since we're gonna meet you know we save
you maxed this lhasa sitting behind the
scenes but
reverts to save
and let's go ahead and do an export
and were export this
q_v_c_ and allen have a pop up in the
web browser and you're going to build
your first
web page of the class
does not inside of some wiki out there
viewport
go down to export slash publish
now i'm gonna show you something real
quick
with he max there's two
funky shortcuts that their runaround
you'll see a lot of
i guarantee you you'll forget this for a
few times until you see it
ten thousand times in this class
you can issue a letter c_
an unusual case he says the capital c a
dash toward casey
indymac speech
that means
press and hold
the controlled heat
i think the more often side of your
keyboard
dash it then
you're not going to do with the dash and
the c_ means
press to see character
it's going to be pulled out of control
perceive once and i might go
and that's going to assure that see you
washed down here at the bottom
there's a little window down here is for
the stylist display what's going on
so i'm holding out of control
pressie
it doesn't look like much has happened
but there's a little
cve dash c
and that's waiting for the next
to go ahead and get control c
so but on the backroom maneuver the menu
yet uh...
the seal seaview
textbook if you keep doing it you're
gonna get more stuff it's gonna get
confused so distressed controls ones
it has lots of extra functionality so it
might do strange things but just press
control see again
which ones
character to now reflect
if you're stuck
control g
here's the quick
indymac
you have gone way ahead uh... lesion
except that
in the kitchen set up his ones that felt
left
simple of
okay
so now there's a breach await your
inheritance someplace else yet so go
ahead this is where you're at it from
so that's a hamburger into a lot of
commands
now if you do after that
control eat
and that was a shortcut that was in this
menu up here
somatic controlled cheated
cats are org
is trying to teach you for cats as you
go so publishes control c control he
ccleaner picked this venue or where
they're from the keyboard so control c
control he
as going to bring up
i'm really crazy looking menu with tons
of stuff
most of what you don't care about
it's going through this and give you a
menu of character she can't wait to get
various forms of output
so you can export as html
latex if you haven't
seem like that before you'll see in this
class it's out waiter markup unrate
papers
there's a docked look if you want to
write a book
there's free mind which is a really neat
mind mapping tool
taps jugular
in which even write her own output
format you can output i'd calendar
and then inquiry into your calendar
system
we're gonna do you have to find it here
under the e_c_ mile section
press the letter p_ e_ which is
exportation elan opening browser
so when you press that he should see
firefox come up
so at the bottom if that is you know
it's work done
push to kill ring and put forward
and it should be starting up firefox
so if you've got your firefox icon if i
down the bottom
click on that
and you're gonna see your example show
up as this issue no page
when a table of contents at all kinds of
features that just magically appear
soleil presby
we deserve it and i'll be back on it but
wrote
there is for windows format forking
delivered a there's been a destruction
when she learned he max
you can use it premature worked appeared
phone
who were deep in the most often they
start to feel for it
and your policy office whether he max
functionality
seated on a city dot let's do something
some action features in here
you've now made a web page
let's put some stuff in here that might
actually matter
uh... then like
dot meeting in keyboard randomly
and if we go
grab a u r l
amber and if you go on something
let's say ccom
so here's the sea com web page
if u
copy back sold to at it
we're gonna piece in here
and you can do you look at it
paste
we now have a lincoln as a special on
underneath us
and if you put your mouse over and you
click on that that's an active link so
anyway to a webpage you put in your
notes
actually takes you to that webpage
so if i put on this
now operations there are there so if we
close out
the sea com web pages
wrapping up my sleeve here his notes
and click on that
you can also so if we just type in one
renew
dadu
a column for example
or
u_n_ age
dot e_d_u_
thank you sir adding links in there
i gets a little massey if we export this
it'll be specific on the strange
but was turned into a list
and if you go to court
can't believe it's got was stuff here
had to actually use the names too often
somewhere in here is probably a list idm
but high no
medalist starts with the dash
so let's put dashes in front of of
each of those lines in the west
so on the wiki we had a slight her
character you put a star here were
putting a dash
at the dash before it was their turns
into a list
and if we export again
you'll say
control c
feels that controls the at the bottom
control eat
you bring up this crazy menu with all
the different options
again renews that be for exporting
nation off the press for derby
and your firefox should generate a new
version of
examples
and if you look down here
a little less than items with whites
if you are linked openly anytime
then you've been right-click and do the
normal firefox things
the web browser
this is always going to open up a tab
so if i could find you know i reject the
young women in the attack
so if you want to have
bookmarks for things that we're not you
can put them in your notes with how i do
links in our class notes
me show you a little bit about
fell lines down here
so he massive has already if you can
track of windows and files and things
done here is your status bar
if you see two starts right here
it means you
haven't save the file so there's been
changes that hadn't been save to desk
so i need to do a file save right here
this is your file name
and then you've got a line number
some online seventeen
and then this is the mode that i meant
so i'm in
org wrote for this file
and as we go three max over the rest of
stress unity things changing out here
you can also do fancy things
and the show you a couple without
actually saying he's right away
we can split into two windows
i can't open up
the direct review at the same time
i can start heading some other file
so here i created one called flew
there's now a stylus line
for each of those
and i want to these commands later on
but only for the basics first so each
one's best estline and here it it
doesn't have any real amount to go with
that doesn't know what a fool filers so
just call the fundamental
so let's go creates a more types of
things in our document
so let's start off
and we'll do something really fancy
let's create table
tables if you press it
the vertical party
which was
when will the clear mind that was the
pipe
and now or create table this is the
first line of the table so this is uh...
column
another
kollam and he's put vertical bars
between
each of your
we get an error nothing happens but if
they go back up here to the swine
press the tab ki
and you have a new line
and we can type
some data
more data
devalue
one two three four
you keep going
if you're inside the table and press
enter it creates a new growth
or you can just do it on your own by
typing in
as long as the first line of that
starts with
that vertical bar you're now inside the
table
you can also create horizontal
separations
supper vertical bar and one or more
dashes
peer in there
pressed tab right after this
all goes well
it fills out the rest of the role with
how it wants to do your a lot like
flying here so it's a bunch of dash is a
plus a bunch of ashes
when we export this we should see what
looks like a nice table
with column headings
hopefully it doesn't raping and makes
them bold or something
you'll then see columns of table so if
you're going up again
called it a report
this is the allies to do it
and let's go ahead
shirt onto another role here
if your
free here any do dash
and the first time
and there could be any spaces
but the dash
renewal i don't have to put down
yet right there
so vertical bars
and then a dash
edit and do you
okay so tune in to a new line below you
physically tired out there to stay on
the bottom
without one
later vertical bar
i dash
now first apt
can you with match
f
there's all kinds of operations in the
table
i will put you at the dock addiction
recovery got behind you all the festival
stuff you can change rose
rose up and down to the columns last
night
all kinds of stuff
if you can do in excel
openoffice
you can probably do it here it just
might be a little okie sometimes
liberating max you'll get to know all
ports of the keyboard
there's lots and lots of shortcuts
if he just if you're in your unstable
brennan
and every sports here
yours and you can also do things like
highlight tax and press two weeks
and you're gonna see this
don't do it you have to understand every
little bit of a plate now
we're going to go through a whole lot
throughout the semester and you'll get
more more comfortable with these
commands as you go
it takes a couple weeks of using the max
to get
a lot of years to get kary at it
but it's very powerful from bsnl us go
ahead
and export again
psalms lysine used the menu
and press the beat
for opening on the browser in regard to
our firefox and see if we have a table
so now we have a little table
and column one and other column of bolts
and we now have a nice to you soon
you can ask for that but that's a
particular style of the authors of this
really liked was
no
for people
there's a
a little special trick you can put in
there and i will show you guys and i
lecture how to make it out
rosenthal's is if you look at
suffering but that's the class notes
you can see that i have more lines in
mind
so i've actually use that trick in the
lecture notes
to add lines
in more detail cert you can control how
that goes
but is it's all a complicated so i'm not
gonna show it to you
and upload all the or requirements for
all of the
lecture notes so you can see all of the
gory details
they have will that work well for our
free you'll see it
in the homework your it should be
working at work both file here to create
in html file you have to give me both
so still a few more
example things
one of the things that i think is going
to be very useful for things like summer
hydro
is a checklist
and if you put it
square brackets
this is considered a checklist
unifies a couple keys
in orkut to get used a lot
control c
is recommended for instance cycle
through things
sophie go up to one of our entries
one entries going to have a dash in the
beginning of the line
there's going to be a space
a lot square bracket
another space
parade square bracket
and in space
and then you write text
so if you press control c
control c_n_n_
and when these lines
a little axe appear and that indicates
that that item is done
now there's lots of
sort of helpers up in the man
the uh... menu appeared
so org
there's two u_s_
properties all kinds of crazy stuff in
here
but decision the basics
sos go ahead and export this one just to
see what it looks like
or publish the letter p
and for whatever here
there's no checklist
down the road you can actually ask were
good to go through your document and
create new gender of things that you
haven't done yet
and that's where we're reversing super
powerful is that
if you work your staff cruiser research
project with their marketing you have to
do
it'll then keep track of what you
haven't haven't done
and give you a summary of that you can
add deadlines and things like that
and be able to manage everything you're
doing a project through
this interface
is every able to
make a checklist with an accident
that's very strange
you'd
they keep n yes
i add avenue on so you guys all have new
lines and i didn't
and hopefully
now if i do have a new line
and is doing things that were bought if
you see this it actually has an author
mark danner
and a date
eyes picking that up out of your account
into using the research tools account
it's not very helpful
and quickens the new ones empress
control g
scenario back to where he should be
kit andar couple times
now doing exports
self control c
control he
and then press the beach character
tonight generating example
let's take a look
control c control sees when you're in
the west that turns on off but check
mark
so if you look at your check mark you
use lower case that's it's gonna wanna
use a capital acts
just respond like this one right here
and press control seized control c
and then again
patrol c control c
tourmaline just press control c controls
the and disappears
so it turns on off without that's done
it's probably out looking like very much
at this point
you know it's a lot of little bits and
pieces that are
creating a much of a whole yet but
it will get through there
in the home repairs who actually gives
you an ice structure to be working from
the show you couple of things that we
can do
if you are insert
i date
press control c
and then a period
it appears hardaway boards figures
control c
and that period
it's gonna bring up a calendar
so now you're facing a calendar
and if he is the mouse you can pick a
date
surfcontrol c_n_n_ period
member controlled she is the quick
character
so we can pick a date anything just
click on a date in there
hopeful stopped yes
if you're not if your british english
that's full stop
yes we just read this last week with
south african
alright nothing haha re happy
you can click on a date
and you know now begin serving i date
every state is special because or quote
actually knows about the date
right so a lot of you are ending up with
split windows were in axis trade tell
you something in a separate window
which you can do
there's a couple of things
down here
this is the that's the wind victoria i
want to split your window we want to do
the opposite so if you've got a split
window like this
we definitely need to know i got back
control
acts and the number one
willow run's what's your window
so if you'd
go ahead and if you don't have a split
window say
split when they're down here
and right below it is the remove splits
and that will endure bread at the two
separate things
we can also do you
if you're pretty crazy they can split
the other direction
and that's
control packs
three
ins split
sideways
and control x to use this play
outbound
any games played and split and split
so freeview too
split this way split that way it's quite
this way
split that way
it can get pretty crazy
then you get control x one can you go
back to that
again with terminology
files
any max think of them as buffers
file people's buffer
in their world so you're probably used
to file dinh
things that have been called file
you can go through and select different
stops if you have lots of things open
you can't switch to different stuff like
we have ac calendar that we used but
still around
said that a buffer sits like calendar
here's that calendar from before
so for example here lost here you want
to get back to your or road
example kota buffers
there's example dot org click on that
beer back here sample
those also i because all four words if
you stuck in multiple windows
it's not fun we don't know what it is
but
move your mouse up
you know the mouse with the pointer
the cursor with the air of keys inside
of your date
move on to you
the year
if you hold on the shift key
and press the up
era buttoned down arrow button
you can change by here
if you move over to the day button you
go up by date down by day
and you'll see the dead week change with
it
so it's pretty easy one insert dates
move things around
now here's where i think it's really
really cool
is we can add source code
so here and you can't relax one
done split
not specialize in the one they have no
control on the one
you've held out of control when you
press once it is to control acts
presents uh...
so which it is the press control acts
then you let go the new president is the
number one by itself
mailto buffers
this is tough and i know you guys art
very different than most acceptors
hang in there
and now scope
food offers in select example dot org
and i left
ad
you can listen michael buffer
you can do it every month to her first
hopefully there's nothing useful in up
offer
you can certainly kill buffer if you'd
like to filibuster
it's going to get a lot easier right
but still interest source code example
begins source passage
this is how we treat here to see these
in your homework
andy
e s r c
and what we got here is a block of
source code it's going to get
highlighted in a little block
and it's going to be colored
so they're kinda helped you out see
what's in there
simply type inside this ako
hello
world
to uh... file save
state idea save and now do another
export college
press that be again
and let's see what we get
and so you should see just like that dot
on the screen up here
of blue border box
with the grey background
and your hello world command in there
so i think taking notes you can write a
paragraph about what you're doing
puts an example code to block
emily export its really nice we
separated for you
now if you go and take a look at the
homework
outpaces into
tickled that link that's your homework
assignment due and a thursday
and if you scroll down
you're gonna see
these blocks of code an affair to longer
fit on the screen it's going to put a
scroll bar and therefore you
so in their homework you're actually
going to be going along and using the
checkboxes and you're gonna get
points off if you haven't checked a box
is done
so use it
to help you out go to the homework as
you go through your download the or mode
file
and you'll be able to your control c
control c here and mark that office don
as you go through these things
you'll be able to that
box here
it's showing you how to run when the
transient iran
and down below as you get into it
pollack put in taxes says
but command here that's where you're
going to a new york mode file type in
your answer to the homework
when you see is worth going to see those
there's also ones were results works not
source code it something that came out
of a program
and i'm gonna switch back to peanuts
and there's another
floppy you can do that isn't highlighted
begin
example
you know that the other
nephew export that
and that's also
for forget put up your comment
in the shell
the town character start to comment
this is k comments
and we export that
yossi different coloring
abortion a color isn't always exactly
same for every version of all of my own
so why do some
slightly different color personally
those export does
and if we go back to our samples
people in firefox
down below you can see the color of this
is our red
warren g_ color
for the comments
and dissection blocked yada yada
it doesn't look any different but he
won't do any highlighting a section
itself to go back to add a comment to
mayor
and they say
what happens
with any comments
say that
for the file save
control c control he
and indeed to publish
built over a simple scroll the bottom
and you can see that
in this example
echoes in this
it's uh...
although it's really hard to see op on
this projector
and down here this comment is for this
british courtesy color
and this one is actually the same color
on the line so it's not good
any highlighting
and would you fight on you will put
python code in their talent that the
languages
i thought of rather than
its own set of s_h_
you can put the word pipe bomb in there
and what then
color as if it's played like codes will
actually understand the language python
figured out for you
so those of the major ones if
though that homework assignments
up at the top
one of things you did you first
is you're going to actually run
this w get commands
and all these commands a merger bid to a
little bit quick your show you
so if we open up a terminal
and we start running these commands that
are in there
so i've opened up might terminals along
then
and not the comeback unmarked these
diamonds fall down
and they do uh... make terror
dash c
surprised
patel victor four u and you can read the
main page exactly what dash p guys but
it creates
mold spore levels a direct result once
so it's going to create the homework
directory end of the two nd delivery
surprise
and i'm gonna go into homework too
with this season and and then i'm gonna
paste in
that debbie that commands
there's also uh... do it
one step at a time and there's a tricky
way to it
i had too many dashes in them
only connections
okay so did the first w commands down
comes this file hands
it's renamed funny
because were using
when u r l
will do move of homework too
and will be rename it's too
have a dot
ordered the ans so homework test tube
homework to take a look at it
we're gonna see an apartment file come
up
and i'm gonna bring up an imax and start
showing you how to work with it so we're
going to go
visit a file
there's gonna be our homework file so
file
open file
and should now have a homework directory
and it too
and inside there will be this or my
father is your homework
so from now on if i can pull it off your
homeworks are all going to be org wrote
files
and allot of it will be filling in
and working with that document and
they're giving back the end result would
be improved
or grow file for the answers
and you're gonna see a lot of formatting
as you go
you don't have to worry about all of it
some of its reform by example as you see
it pipes
up at the top
we have some fancy stuff which is
kiryat gat you can set the
authornamehandle email
if i see of your remarks with
fix colin in the end result except for
the paragraph it talks about this whole
one
then you know it's a points the are use
that as a tax string to mark where you
need to be putting in answers
but as we go down here
so here's the cd list and as i go
through that i'm in a hit control c
control c
the virtual machine section
open up a terminal do that
c
i made the directories okay we've got
at that one
added ran the w get command have renamed
its
and i've opened up anything that's them
here i am side now check goes off
when you finish a section
we're going to the special thing work
and flight things is to do you worked on
and to go to new york
section of here and he had a retreat can
be marked
has to do or done
that u_s_
fifteen bucks at
menu option
to s
don to do dash
the next one hopefully if i remember my
orwell right should be nothing
nowads not marked as two you'll have
done it it doesn't happen stats on it
can you can get really crazy and make
your own of if you want
so again we can go in
we'll set that is done
humorless
to control c controls the instead
the plan for that
or use the menu will mark that is done
any move on the neck section when you're
finished for the homework there should
be no choose it should be all done
all of the checkboxes should have a
check in them
all of the fixes it should be caught
so as you work through it
how you'll start doing things like every
time you see one of these boxes it means
you need to do something
so he returned one four u sorting out of
work mode
i've gone off and at the question is
what is the secom website so i pasted
into your office he com website and i've
marked it
with an action that's trotsky control c
so you were through those answer some
questions
build this up as you go
it's going to walk you back for some the
examples that we did with the command
line
it'll be dull in some data was actually
ship tracks awful boston and hopefully
next time we'll actually
view where the shift went
ill download this this comma-separated
value file
and uncompressed that's
and you'll start working with that
you'll norwalk if your own compressing
the file here it says fix put command
here your place the commanding in that
without text is
and job and go down and you know
run they like the file commander figure
out what type of file it is
use the head and tail commands like just
giving you a big unfair
the views that before but i'm not sure
of mentioned field
and you work for all of that
at the bottom
in a walking through creating a tar file
of your
which you refused to take that were good
final
and put into a directory and univ also
click
is gmail export in that directory you
get a build up a single tart file
you're gonna calculate the check some of
it and you have to email me the check
song
and put that file on that
the research tools computer
so you're not going to email me your
homework you email me just checked some
of your homework
i know that you know i think it's good
and the idea of this is that i can
verify got homework is the home or do
you think you've got
it's not very exciting in this case but
imagine tens of thousands of homeworks
or tens of thousands of surveys
and if you have a file for the check
sounds you can validate that you have
all of them very easily
so i'm doing some things are kind of
goofy and weird
but in the long run you're gonna start
seeing the patterns and hopefully
they'll start picking up some of the
tracks
so if someone says here's the mt five
checks on the phone file you'll actually
no
what to do you have check it
i start building up that library tools
that will let you work with huge amounts
of data very efficiently
to get the homework ago
i will do even more of this on thursday
and hopefull will start making some
plots
i promise we will make a movie of the
key
the law for today
stark a_b_c_ max give it a go
ask lots of questions on thursday